- We got to get back. - See ya, Matt.
- 我们得回船了 - 再见麦特…
Come through here.
由这里过去
Open up.
张开嘴
Welcome to Alcatraz.
欢迎你来亚卡拉
Inside B and C! Count them!
B座和C座开始点数！
- 25 on inside C, first tier. - 20 inside B, first tier.
C座第二层二十五名！ B座第二层二十名！
- 23 on inside C, second tier. - 17 inside B, second tier.
C座第三层二十三名！ B座第三层十七名！
Break out! Inside B and C.
B座和C座的出来！
Move!
快点！
Better button your collar, boy.
你最好扣上钮扣
No forks.
没有叉子？
Hey, no forks.
没有叉子
Do you see any?
你看到叉子吗？
Fresh fish, you want your pasta?
新来的人，你要面条吗？
Hey, you want your pasta?
你要吗？
Do you see any?
你看到吗？
I see pasta in my sleep.
我在梦中也看见面条
I'm Litmus.
我叫李末斯
Like litmus paper.
像试纸
When it's cold, my face gets blue.
天冷时我脸变蓝色
When it's hot, my face gets red.
天热我脸就变红色
Inside C, move out.
进入C座！出去！
Warden wants to see you.
监狱长要见你
- Name? - Morris.
姓名？ 摩立斯
That's funny.
奇怪
This file says Frank Lee Morris.
文件说是法莱李摩立斯
If you disobey the rules of society, they send you to prison.
你犯法就被送入狱
If you disobey the rules of prison, they send you to us.
违反狱中规律就送来这里
Alcatraz is not like any other prison in the United States.
亚卡拉和美国其他监狱不同
Here, every inmate is confined alone
在这里，每间囚室 只监禁一名犯人
to an individual cell.
我的作风
Unlike my predecessors,
跟两位前任监狱长不同
wardens Johnson and Blackwell,
Johnson 和 Blackwell监狱长
I don't have good conduct programs.
我没有行为良好方案
I do not have inmate councils.
也没有囚犯委员会
Inmates have no say in what they do.
这里的犯人
They do as they're told.
必须绝对服从命令
You are not permitted
你们不准
to have newspapers or magazines carrying news.
阅读报章或新闻性杂志
Knowledge of the outside world is what we tell you.
外界新闻全凭我们传达
From this day on,
由今天起
your world will be everything that happens in this building.
你的世界只局限于 在这建筑物发生的一切
You will shave once a day.
你每天将剃须一次
You will shower twice a week.
每周淋浴两次
You will cut your hair once a month.
每月理发一次
Now, your privileges.
现在关于你的权利
You can talk. You can work. Other institutions hand out work,
你可以说话和工作 其他监狱是分配工作
but here it's a privilege that you earn.
但在这里赚钱是权利
I promise you it's a privilege that you'll want.
我保证你渴望获此权利
Visitors - you're allowed two a month.
每月准许探访两次
They cannot be former inmates of this or any other federal prison.
但这里不准释囚到访的
All names that you submit will be carefully checked by the FBI.
你提交的名单将遭严密审查
What names do you have in mind?
你心目中有什么姓名？
I can't think of any offhand.
我一时想不起来
Family members?
家人？
None. No family.
我没有家人
Alcatraz is a maximum security prison
亚卡拉是高度设防监狱
with very few privileges.
权利却很少
We don't make good citizens,
这里没有良好市民
but we make good prisoners.
但我们能训练模范囚犯
Burglary, armed robbery,
盗窃、持械、抢劫
grand larceny...
grand larceny...
That's why you're here.
因此你在这里
Alcatraz was built to keep all the rotten eggs in one basket.
这里监禁所有坏蛋
I was specially chosen
我被选派
to ensure that the stink from the basket does not escape.
确保坏蛋不会越狱
Since I've been warden some have tried to escape.
我到任后，有几个企图逃狱
Most have been recaptured. Those who haven't have been killed
多数被捕获 其余的被杀死
or drowned in the bay.
或淹死
No one has ever escaped from Alcatraz.
从来没有人成功越狱
And no one ever will.
将来也不会有人成功
- You two go everywhere together? - Sure. Even to bed together.
你们形影不离？ 当然，我们还一起上床
When I wash, he washes.
一同沐浴，因此睡得清洁舒服
That way we sleep nice-nice together. Capisce?
因此睡得清洁舒服
I'm Wolf.
我是狼
Where did they transfer you from?
他们把你从哪儿转来？
Atlanta.
亚特兰大
Nice town, Atlanta.
好城市…亚特兰大
I never saw it.
我从未看过它的风光
I'm looking for a new punk.
我在找寻新伴侣
Good luck.
祝你好运
You don't understand. I just found her.
你不明白，我方才找到她了
Why don't you show her what you can do?
你何不向她显些本领？
Morris, I need somebody in the library.
摩立斯，图书馆需要人
- Take him over there, will you? - Yes, captain. Move.
-带他到那里去 -是，队长，走吧
What you want, boy?
你来做什么，孩子？
The bull sent me down here to work.
狱卒叫我来工作
Can you read, boy?
你识字吗，孩子？
As long as it's in the English language, boy.
只要是英文就识，孩子
You treat them all like Wolf?
你对待他们都像对狼一样？
Wolf wanted to get friendly. I didn't.
狼想套交情，我不愿意
You'll take that cart to the cells.
你推那车去牢房
Don't they let cons down here?
他们不准许囚犯来这里吗？
You see any chairs?
你看见椅子吗？
How come?
为什么？
Because this is The Rock, man.
因为这里是岩石
They don't want you doing anything here, but time...
他们只要你在此过日子
Hard friggin' time.
艰难怪诞的日子
Rock affects dudes differently.
岩石对人们有特殊影响
It either brings out your strength,
它不是增强你力量
or it breaks you.
就是摧毁你
What did it do for you?
它对你影响如何？
What happens when you get out?
你出狱后有何打算？
I won't.
我永远不能出狱
10 years ago...
十年前…
I was in this bar in Alabama
我在酒吧
when two dudes started hassling me.
跟两个人争吵
That was their first mistake.
那是他们第一个错误
They pulled knives. That was their second mistake.
他们拔刀 那是他们第二个错误
They didn't know how to use them.
他们不擅用刀
That was the last mistake they ever made.
那是他们最后错误
I got two 99-year sentences back-to-back.
结果我被判两个九十九年徒刑
Seems like you could have pleaded self-defence.
你可以用自卫作辩护
The dudes were white, man,
他俩都是白人！
just like you.
跟你一样，
When I arrived they put me in one of those dark cells in D-block.
我刚进来 就被囚禁在D座黑暗牢房
After a while, I went stir crazy.
不久我发疯了
Sliced my Achilles' tendon to get out.
我割了腿腱企图离开牢房
You'll see why when you see D-block.
你见到D座就会知道原因
Tell me something, you through killing white guys?
你不再杀白人了？
- Why? - Well, I don't know.
为什么？ 我不知道
I just figured I wouldn't turn my back on you.
我以后不会背朝着你
Hey.
Hey.
What's your name, man?
你叫什么名字？
Frank. What's yours?
法莱，你呢？
English.
英利斯
See you later.
一会再见
- Your name? - Morris.
-你的姓名？ -摩立斯
OK.
进来吧
- Magazine or book? - Where's English?
要杂志还是要书？
What did they do, give a nigger a nigger of his own?
他们给黑人一个 自己喜欢的黑人？
Magazine?
杂志？
- Hi! I'm Bugsy. - Magazine or book?
- Hi! I'm Bugsy. -要杂志还是要书？
Thanks. Hey, you're new.
-谢谢. 你是新来的
Yeah.
-是
Hey, wait, wait a minute.
等一下…
I haven't seen a new guy in six months.
我六个月来没见过新人
It's nice to talk. How are the Brooklyn Dodgers doing?
交谈的感觉蛮好的 布鲁克林道奇队成绩如何？
- Moved to LA two years ago. - No kidding?
他们两年前搬去了洛杉矶 没看玩笑吧？
Warden don't allow books in these cells.
监狱长不准在这些牢房阅读
How come?
为什么？
Because there's no light in them.
因为那里没有灯
Better deliver them books, Morris,
你还是去有光线
where they can be read.
能阅读的地方
Right.
是的
What's the flower?
那花做什么的？
That's something inside me
那是深藏我心中的东西…
they can't lock up with their bars and walls.
他们不能将它锁住
I'm Doc.
我是医生
You ever paint?
你会绘画吗？
- No. - Why not?
-不 -为什么？
You scared of dying?
你怕死吗？
- I don't think so. - You better be.
我想不会的 小心些
You hurt Wolf. Wolf's going to hurt you.
你伤害了狼 狼会伤害你
Where you going, cracker?
你去哪里？
Pete.
皮特
Something special about those steps?
这些梯级有什么特别？
The higher you sit, the more status you got.
坐得越高，地位越重要
So we play king of the mountain,
我们玩山岭国王游戏
except here we don't play for fun, man.
但我们并不是开玩笑的
And you're king?
你是国王？
Yeah.
是
Now, I figure there's two reasons
有两个理由你不愿坐我下面
why you didn't sit down on my step.
你不愿坐我下面
Either you're too scared,
不是你害怕
or you just hate niggers.
就是你痛恨黑人
Now, which is it, boy? You too scared?
到底是什么？你太害怕吗？
I just hate niggers.
我只是讨厌黑人
So no one's ever busted out.
从来没有人能越狱
Everyone has looked for a way, but there ain't any.
各人都苦无对策
See those hacks?
见到那狱卒吗？
Most joints have one hack for every seven cons.
在别的监狱 一名狱卒看守七个囚犯
There's one hack for every three cons here.
这里三个囚犯就有一名狱卒
You start shitting at night instead of in the morning,
我们改变上厕所时间
they want to know why.
他们也要问
Let's say you're going to try it anyway.
假定你无论如何要试一试
First, you've got to get out of the cell.
首先你须逃出牢房
Each bar has six hard smaller bars
每一钢管内有六支小铁条
set in a steel tube with extra steel poured in.
再用钢灌满它
And there ain't no way to tunnel out, either.
也没有办法掘地道
Shit.
真该死
This island is solid rock.
这岛是一座岩石
See that water?
见到那海水吗？
It's over a mile swim to land.
游超过一哩才能登陆
The currents make it seem like 10.
那水流令人好像游十哩之多
And the water's so cold it will numb your arms in minutes.
海水数分钟内冷得你手臂麻木
Even if you are a good swimmer, you won't have time to make it.
即使你是游泳健将也无法成功
There are 12 counts every day.
他们每天点名十二次
Sometimes I think that's all this shit hole is,
这讨厌的地狱整天就是点数
one long count.
不断的点数
We count the hours,
我们计算时间，
the bulls count us,
狱卒点算我们
and the king bulls count the counts.
再由监狱长核对
Inside! Everybody in!
各人进入牢房！
I'm assigning you a permanent job.
我给你一份固定差事
Weather here is as crazy as The Rock. Maybe crazier.
这里的气候和岩石一样 或许更疯狂
Mark Twain wrote that the coldest winter he ever spent
麦克吐温曾经这样写 他在三藩市夏季
was a summer in San Francisco. I can...
度过最寒冷的冬天
Wolf's coming at you.
狼向着你过来
- Is his hand cupped? - Yes.
-他紧握拳头吗？ -是
- Which one? - His right.
-哪一只手？ -右手
Break off!
停止打斗！
Drop it, Wolf!
狼！ 丢掉小刀
You like D-block, Wolf?
你喜欢D座吗？狼？
You better, because you're gonna rot there for a long time.
你最好喜欢。 你将会长时间呆在那里发臭
D-block, Morris.
D座，摩立斯
Look, he came at me.
是他袭击我
I said D-block.
我说D座
When I get out, you're dead.
我离开这里时你就没命
You'll be dead before you get out.
你离开前也许已经死了！
Warden don't like inmates fighting.
监狱长不喜欢囚犯打架
Don't like 'em stinking up their cells, either.
也不喜欢他们弄脏囚室
Lights out!
熄灯！
Go on back to your cell.
你回囚室去
Welcome to Alcatraz.
（欢迎你回来，李末斯）
- Hey, is anybody over there? - Yeah, me.
有人在那里吗 我在
Come out in front and say hello.
上前来问候一声
Busy.
我很忙
How busy can you be in one of these closets?
你在厕所能有多忙？
Don't worry. I washed it.
别担心，我洗干净了
How you doing, neighbour? I'm Charley Butts.
你好吗？我是差利毕兹
Smallest cell I ever been in.
这是我住过最小的牢房 你会习惯的 不会，
I don't like living alone here.
我不喜欢独居牢房
You'll get used to that, too.
你也会习惯的
Break out!
离开囚室！
Yard time!
去广场！
Button the collar.
扣上衣领
Who's the new fish?
这个新人是谁？
I got him next to me.
他住在我隔壁
- What's your name? - Charley Butts.
-你叫什么名字？ -差利毕兹
Charley's butt?
差利屁股（同音）
Butts. Butts. Charley Butts.
毕兹…差利毕兹！
You got a funny name, kid.
你姓名很奇怪
Yeah? What's your name?
是吗？你叫什么名字？
Al Capone.
亚卡潘尼（著名匪徒）
Thought you were dead.
还以为你死了
Me? I got too much money. I'll never die.
我的财富数之不尽 我不会死的
- You play poker? - Not much.
-你玩扑克牌吗？ -不太会
I just learned myself. We'll play tomorrow.
我刚刚学晓了，明天一起玩吧
See you later, kid.
再见
I don't believe I just met Al Capone.
我不相信刚才遇见了亚卡潘尼
I don't, either.
我也不信
- I'm Doc. - Charley Butts.
-我是医生 -我是差利毕兹
How's the painting going, Doc?
你画得如何？
The one of the warden? It's nearly finished.
你指那监狱长画像？ 差不多完成了
- You painting the warden? - He's very inspiring.
你画监狱长的肖像？ 很能鼓舞人心
Inside. Everybody in.
各人返回囚室！
Yes, sir?
监狱长
I want painting privileges taken away from Chester Dalton.
我要剥夺道顿的绘画权利
- Doc? - Cell 233.
医生？ 第233号囚室
What's the reason?
什么理由？
You're deputy warden. You think of one.
你是副监狱长，你想个理由
When do you want the suspension to begin?
暂停绘画何时开始？
It's not a suspension. It's an elimination.
不是暂停，是永久取消
- Right away. - Yes, sir.
立刻去执行
Painting privileges have been removed.
你绘画的权利已被取消
Why?
为什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
Painting's all I have.
绘画是我唯一的爱好
I'm sorry, Doc.
我很抱歉，医生.
You OK, Doc?
你没事吧，医生？
I think there's something wrong with him.
他有点不妥
I'd keep my eye on Doc. He seems pretty upset.
你要留意医生，他心烦意乱
Cons are always upset about something.
囚犯总是如此，
Put your overalls on.
穿上你的工衣
Mr. Zimmerman, I'm making a new table.
薛茂曼先生？ 我造新桌子
I need a hatchet.
需要短柄斧
Bob, get Doc a hatchet.
阿卜，给医生一把短柄斧
Mr. Zimmerman!
薜茂曼先生？
Can you come over here for a minute?
请到这里
Get him out of here! Get him out!
把他带走…
Take him out of here! Get him out!
快把他带离这里
Get back to work.
继续工作！
Let's go! Move!
去！
Everybody, back to work! Let's go!
各人继续工作，去！
Here. Put that in your report.
将这个写在你报告里
What were you doing back there, boy?
你在那里干什么？
- How about a magazine? - Why not?
要杂志吗？ 好
What do you want? Boy's Life?
你要什么杂志？我有“男孩生活”
I know some queens who fight over it every month.
同性恋者每月都为了它打架
Just give me what you got on top there.
只要给我上面那本
I heard about Doc,
我听到了医生的事
and I know why he did it.
我知道他为何如此干
Somebody took away his painting privileges.
有人剥夺了他的绘画权利
Who?
谁？
The warden.
监狱长
Morris.
摩立斯！
I hear there was an accident in one of the shops.
-监狱长 -听说工场发生了一件小意外
Accident? You mean Doc.
意外？你指医生
Yeah, someone didn't like what he was painting,
似乎有人不喜欢他的画
so someone won't let him paint.
因此禁止他绘画
Someone should have warned Doc to be careful what he paints.
有人应该警告他绘画要小心些
I think you're absolutely right, sir.
你说得很对
There's always the possibility
很可能得罪了一些混蛋
that some asshole will be offended, isn't there?
-不是有这类人吗？
We all have to be careful.
-我们都必须小心
Back in line.
回去工作
Hey, how's it going, Frank?
法莱，你好吗？
Well, well. If it isn't the Anglins.
原来是安格琳兄弟
What are you guys doing, just dropping by?
怎么了？顺道来探访吗？?
- Thought we'd pay you a visit. - Gonna stay long?
不错，我们来拜访你 -逗留很久吗？
Not long. Only about 15 or 20 years.
-不会很久，只是十五至二十年
Why The Rock?
为什么来这里？
We were leaving Atlanta when we encountered a minor problem.
我们在亚特兰大越狱时 发生了问题
- Such as? - They saw us.
-例如呢？ -被他们发觉了
Yeah, that do present problems.
的确是个问题
They shipped us to Leavenworth.
他们将我们送到莱文沃思服刑
But we didn't like their accommodations, either.
但我们也不喜欢那里的环境
Warden said he knew just the place for us...Alcatraz.
因此狱长就送我们来这里
Is it true no one's ever bust out of here?
真的从来没有人逃出这里吗？
- So they tell me. - Jesus.
他们是这样告诉我的
Wonder what I'd be like after 15 years here.
真想知道我15年后是什么样。
You still reading that bible?
你仍在读圣经？
Yeah. It's opening up all kinds of new doors.
是，它给我许多启发
I turned 35 today. Some birthday.
今天是我三十五岁生日
- When's your birthday? - I don't know.
你何时生日？ 我不知道
Jeez, what kind of childhood did you have?
你童年是怎样过的？
Short.
十分短促
I always wanted to see San Francisco. Never thought it'd be like this.
我一直渴望要来三藩市见识 没料到结果会是这样
What'd you get sent to the rock for?
你为何被送来这里？
Couple of years ago I started stealing cars, for kicks mostly.
几年前我开始偷车 主要是为了找寻刺激
I'd sell the parts. Got sent to the state pen.
有时也会将车拆散后售卖零件 结果被送去州立监狱
You end up in Alcatraz for that?
就是这个原因被送到这里
Not exactly. A bull there liked to push me around.
不，有个狱卒常欺负我
So when I got out, I went back, and stole his car.
出狱后…我去偷他的车
Unfortunately, I drove it across the state line,
我开着它越过州界
which made it a federal rap, and I was sent to the rock.
触犯了联邦法律 那狱卒立心将我送到这里
English! Visitor for you.
英利斯！有人探访你
Butts, you got a visitor.
毕兹！你有访客
- Me? - Yeah, you.
-我？ -不错，是你
Probably somebody wants their car back.
或许有人想向你索回偷车
Hello, father.
你好，爸爸
Why didn't you say you were coming?
怎么不告诉我你要来？
I was afraid you wouldn't let me.
我怕你不让我来
It's just hard to see you like this.
这样见到你，我很难过 你妈妈快死了
Charley?
差利…
When?
大约何时？
Well, she's got a few months.
她只可以活几个月
Can you call her?
你可以打电话给她吗？
We're not allowed to make phone calls.
这里不准打电话的
You cannot discuss institution rules. Stick to your personal life.
不准讨论监狱规则 只可谈论你个人生活
This is my personal life! You getting a kick out of it?
这是我个人生活 你觉得很刺激？
Hello?
Hello?
Hello!
Hello!
I...love...you...Charley.
我爱你…差利
Hey, Frank.
法莱？
Yeah?
什么事？
If you try to get out, I want in.
你要逃狱的话，我愿意参加
- Must be Wednesday. - Why?
今天一定是星期三 为什么？
Mystery mounds.
神秘菜肴
We always have mystery mounds on Wednesday.
星期三总是吃神秘菜肴
I can't taste it. I just eat it out of habit.
我已不知味道 只是习惯地吃它
- What's the movie this weekend? - Some cowboy piece of shit.
本周末放什么电影？ 三四流的西部片
Hey, at least they could show us a gangster movie.
他们至少可以放部警匪片
I may have found a way out of here.
我或许有办法逃离这里
You looking at something?
你在看什么？
This cell block's really getting old.
整个牢狱已很残旧
The moist air corrodes the concrete. The salt is rusting the metal.
潮湿的空气将水泥腐蚀 盐令金属生锈
I took a nail clipper, and dug around the grille at the back of the cell.
我用指甲钳 掘囚室后面的铁栅
I can dig that grille out,
花一点工夫
and enlarge the hole into the utility corridor
就可以把铁栅掘大
to the top of the cell block and maybe onto the roof.
进入公用通道通往楼座顶部 或许爬上屋顶
How will we hide the hole?
我们掘洞时如何遮掩它？
We tear the ads from magazines... no one will miss those...
可以撕下杂志上的广告
make cardboard, paint grilles on that, and put it in the hole,
制成纸板，画上铁栅将洞遮住
maybe partially obscure it with a towel or whatever.
或许再用毛巾浴袍在前遮掩
I've ordered an accordion to put in front of my hole.
我将用手风琴遮盖洞口
Suppose we make it. They'll know we're gone at the next count.
假设我们逃出牢房 但他们点数时就会发觉
We'll leave at night, so they won't know till the morning.
晚上越狱 他们到早上才会察觉
We'll have to make some dummy heads,
我们用纸板之类做些假人头
make them out of plaster or cardboard or whatever.
放在床上，狱卒不会发觉 如何渡过海湾？
That's your job. You work in the clothing shop.
尊，你在服装工场工作
You're gonna steal some raincoats and some contact cement.
设法偷取雨衣和水泥胶
We'll make a life raft and some life preservers.
用它们制成救生筏和救生衣
I read how to do it in Popular Mechanics.
我看过杂志知道如何制造
They'll think we're going to Frisco.
他们会以为我们去三藩市
Well, we won't. We'll go to Angel Island instead.
其实不然，我们将逃往天使岛
What about me?
我怎样？
You'll stand guard while I dig. I'll stand guard while you dig.
我们轮流看守和掘洞
You two trade off the same way.
你们二人也同样工作
What are our chances?
我们机会如何？
Slim.
机会很微
- I'm in. - Me, too.
-我加入 -我也是
I wanna go.
我要离开
Charley.
差利
Yeah?
Yeah?
I'm gonna start digging. Keep an eye out.
我开始掘洞，你注意狱卒
If you see one, start whistling, huh?
见有人来就吹口哨
How's it going?
情况如何？
Fair.
还好
Whoever named this place The Rock wasn't kidding.
Whoever named this place The Rock wasn't kidding.
Working with those nail clippers just doesn't have any grip.
Working with those nail clippers just doesn't have any grip.
Hey, guard.
狱警
Yeah?
Yeah?
Can I exchange this spoon? Looks like it's been in someone's ass.
这餐匙很肮脏，可否换一个？
And I want to work in the kitchen.
我想查询到厨房工作的详情
- Go ahead. - Thank you.
去吧 - Thank you.
I'd like to join the kitchen detail.
-我想在厨房工作
Can you cook?
-你能烹调吗？
Can I swap this spoon for another?
这匙太锋利，可以换一个吗？
Damn right I can cook.
我是煮餐能手
I used to be a cook in this cafe. Everybody loved my meatballs.
我在乔治亚州做过快餐厨师 Everybody loved my meatballs.
Did you quit or get fired?
后来你辞职还是被解雇？
Neither. I robbed the cafe.
不，我抢劫了餐室
- Heard you had a visitor. - My daughter.
听说你有访客 我女儿，
She's getting married.
她要结婚了 他是白人，像你一样
just like you.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
Congratulations.
- Want a magazine? - Yeah. What do you recommend?
要杂志吗？ - Yeah. What do you recommend?
Ebony.
“乌木杂志”（黑人杂志）
Hey, English.
英利斯
Is it possible to weld two pieces of metal together here in the cell?
在囚室里可以焊接两片金属吗
For digging...or sticking?
用来掘洞还是杀人？
Digging.
掘洞
It ain't easy, but I could show you.
不容易的，但我可以教你
Planning on going somewhere?
打算去别的地方？
There hasn't been a day that I've been on this rock
我在这里时刻都想逃狱
that I didn't think of busting out.
如果我割腱时知道如此
If I'd known, I'd have slashed my throat instead of my tendon.
当时我一定会割喉
Hey, Litmus, can you get me a dime?
李末斯,可否给我一角钱？
No problem. Cost you 10 desserts.
没问题，以十个甜点交换
I need it tonight.
-我今晚需要它
No problem. Cost you an extra five.
-没问题，再要你五个甜点
Get me a dime, I'll toss in 10 beetles for your mouse.
给我一角 我送十只甲虫给你的老鼠
Thanks.
谢谢
Hey, Frank, what's burning?
法莱，你在烧什么？
If you see one of those bulls coming, just start whistling.
你见到狱卒来就吹口哨
Hey, Spoof, what's for breakfast?
早餐吃什么？
I smell something burning.
我闻到烧焦的气味
I don't smell anything.
我没有闻到什么
Hell, must be my imagination.
不错，或许是我的幻觉
Working nights really gets to you after a while.
晚上工作真会令人失常
Try it from my side.
你该尝试做囚犯的滋味
Keep an eye out. He may be back.
小心些，他或许再会回来
The grille's welded on two-hook anchors?
铁栅焊接在两支勾住的桩上？
This might just be what I'm looking for.
这就是我需要的东西
But it won't get through the metal detector.
但你会被金属侦察器发觉
Yeah, I know.
我知道
Morris, hold it.
摩立斯，停步
I made it for a clothes-peg.
我用来做挂衣钉
Why the metal over the edge?
边缘为什么会有金属？
So the clothes would slide off easy.
衣服容易滑落
I don't believe you.
我不相信
I didn't try to hide it. Why would I try to take metal through a detector?
我无意隐藏 我为何要让侦察器发觉？
Because you're stupid.
因为你蠢
Move it.
走吧
Open up 107.
开启107室
Why did you order this stuff? You don't look like a painter.
你要这些做什么？ 你不像是画家
You wouldn't know talent if it looked you in the face.
你根本不知道天才是什么 ！
I'm looking you in the face and I don't see shit.
我面前就站着个大笨蛋
Hair. Your colour.
头发…你的颜色
Frank.
法莱？
Paint. One of them's flesh-coloured.
颜料，其中一种肉色 你画什么？
I don't know. The ocean maybe.
我不知道，或许海洋
If you're using flesh-coloured paint, you better paint a portrait.
你如果用肉色颜料 最好画肖像
Yeah.
Yeah.
Frank.
法莱！
Morris go to sleep early tonight?
摩立斯今晚睡得早？
Yeah. Wasn't feeling well.
他不舒服
He must sleep pretty soundly. He hasn't moved.
他一定睡得很熟，动都不动！
Morris?
摩立斯？
Yeah, what's up?
什么事？
I went up top last night.
我昨晚去过楼顶
I saw the ventilator shaft to the roof, but I can't reach it.
但无法爬上通风管道
I need a boost.
要人帮助
How are you all coming?
你们进展得如何？
My dummy's ready.
我的假人已准备好
The hole's done, but I'm just starting the dummy.
我已掘好洞 但假人刚刚才开始做
I ain't doing too good.
我进度不太好
Tonight, John and I will go up.
今晚尊和我上去
You get those raincoats, might as well start hauling them up.
你可以向服装工场拿到雨衣？ 我们开始积聚起来
I'll wear one back from the shop each day.
我每天穿一件回去
There's a different hack there in the afternoon.
下午看守牢门的狱警会换班
He'll think I wore it to work.
他会以为我穿雨衣去工作
- Can you get that contact cement? - I keep inventory.
你可以取得水泥胶吗？ 存货由我管理
Hey!
Hey!
Give me a boost.
Give me a boost.
The bars feel pretty solid.
铁枝似乎很结实
There seems to be a metal hood riveted onto higher uprights.
有金属罩铆在铁柱上
We'll spread the bars with a pipe and knock the hood off.
可用铁管将铁枝扩展敲去铁罩
There's an electrical outlet here.
如果有发动机、钻头
Get a motor, a drill bit and a flashlight and we'd have it all.
和电筒就行了
Great. Where's the nearest hardware store?
最近的五金店在哪里？
Can you get me an extension cord and a drill bit from the shop?
能给我一些电线和钻头吗？
If they find out, I go to the hole.
被发觉的话，我会去D座黑房
All right, but from now on, you put your desserts onto my tray.
今后将你的甜点放在我的盘中
Time's up. Back to the cells.
各人回房去
Damn it! Just when I thought we was doing good.
该死！正玩得高兴便要停
I can use this.
I can use this.
Are you crazy?
你疯了吗？
Hold it, Morris.
等一下，摩立斯
Want to look at one of those cases.
我要检查乐器箱
Try this one.
检查这个
Let's open it up.
将它开启
Stole this penlight from the Doc.
那是史东的小电筒
Hey.
Hey.
Give me a boost.
把我托上去
Pipe.
铁管
OK. Hand me the drill.
给我电钻
We're all through.
We're all through.
Fire!
开火！
Hey, 50-millimetre guns.
五十毫米小钢炮
I'm worried about the shakedowns.
我怕被搜查
My cardboard grille keeps slipping out.
纸板不断滑落
Put some contact cement around the edges.
四边用水泥粘住就没事了
That should take care of it.
That should take care of it.
How's the raft and the life jackets coming?
How's the raft and the life jackets coming?
OK.
OK.
I think they'll be done Tuesday.
星期二可以准备妥当
Tuesday night, we go.
星期二晚我们启程
What's that for?
那做什么？
Just thinking about Doc.
我想起医生
Yeah. We planted those chrysanthemums 15 years ago.
我们十五年前种那些菊花
They meant a lot to Doc. To me, too.
它们对医生和我意义重大
- I had a garden. - What'd you grow, weeds?
我从前也有个花园 你种什么？野草？
It's against regulations, Morris, and you know it.
你知道这是触犯规则的
Stretcher.
担架床
Get the medic.
我去找医生来
He won't need one.
他已不再需要了
Some men are destined never to leave Alcatraz...
有些人注定永远要留在亚卡拉
alive.
到死为止
Got those books that may help you.
这些书对你有帮助
Thanks.
谢谢
See you later, man.
再会
Goodbye...boy.
再会，孩子
Shakedown.
搜查
Move.
起来…
Move, move, move.
Move, move, move.
Take a seat.
坐下
- Been playing this thing long? - Couple of months.
你玩了多久？ 几个月
- You any good? - Terrible.
弹得好吗？ 糟极了
You'll get better.
你会进步的
Excuse me.
对不起
That's one of the benefits of Alcatraz.
这就是亚卡拉好处之一
Lots of time to practise.
有很多时间练习
Has Morris been doing anything unusual?
摩立斯最近有不寻常的活动吗
Sometimes he stays up late talking with Butts.
他有时很晚仍和毕兹交谈
Split them up. Move Morris.
将他们分开，移走摩立斯
I'll have to get a cell ready and do the paperwork.
是的，但我要准备另一个囚室 和办理手续…
- Do you? - Yes, sir.
是吗？ - Yes, sir.
We could move him, say, Wednesday.
星期三可以将他移走
- Tuesday morning. - Yes, sir.
星期二早上 - Yes, sir.
I missed you, Morris.
我想念你
I missed you so much, I got a present for you.
太想念你了，我要送你礼物
I'll give it to you...later.
我稍后送给你
Get your ass back there.
回到那里去
He'll kill you, or you'll have to kill him.
不是他杀你就是你杀他
Well, I'm not going to give him the chance.
我不会给他机会下手
Can you get the raft and life jackets ready by tonight?
今晚准备好救生筏和救生衣吗
All right.
好的
We'll meet on top as soon as the lights are out.
熄灯后我们在上面会面
- Wolf, you carrying? - Who, me?
狼，你带了武器吗？ 谁？我？
Move out.
去吧
Where you going, Wolfie?
你去哪里，狼？
I'm just going for a walk.
我正要去散步
Let's take that walk.
我们一起散步吧
After six months in the hole,
你被囚禁黑房半年
looks like you could use some exercise.
需要运动一下
Butts.
毕兹！
I'll meet you up on top.
我在上面见你
Let's go.
你也一同去吧
Yeah. You're going, too.
毕兹！
Butts.
毕兹
Butts, God damn it.
该死！
Can't risk tearing this gear, what's left of it.
不能冒险让它撕裂
Throw me the stuff when I get over.
我爬过去后把东西抛给我
Get up, Morris. It's moving day.
起来，要把你搬走了
I said, get up, Morris. Open up 109.
起来，摩立斯！开启109室
God damn it, Morris. I said get...
该死，摩立斯！我叫你起来…
Jesus Christ.
我的天！
Morning, Sergeant. What have you got?
早安，警官，这是什么？
Photos and a notebook of Clarence Anglin's.
安格琳的照片和记事簿
Funny looking bag.
形状奇怪，
Must have been made from a raincoat.
一定是用雨衣做的
- It appears that they drowned. - Why?
-看来他们淹死了 -为什么？
If that was important they wouldn't have lost it.
他们不会遗留如此重要的东西
Maybe they lost it to look like they drowned.
或许他们故意留下装作淹死
Warden, I just got a message from the Director.
我们刚接到处长口讯
He wants you in Washington.
他想你乘下一班机去华盛顿
Do chrysanthemums grow on this island?
这个岛生长菊花吗？
Not here on Angel Island. Why?
我不记得有，为什么？
I'm curious.
我很好奇
The tides were mild and the fog light last night.
昨晚潮水和缓，雾很稀薄
If they left at lights out, they had a 9 1/2-hour head start.
他们若是熄灯后离开 九个小时半前已行动
I wonder if they made it.
我不知道他们能否成功
They drowned.
他们淹死了
Yes, sir.
是的